# STEPHEN CHARLES

#### **OVERVIEW**

Portfolic

Proficient *pythonista* with a background in mathematics and computer science. Particular expertise in managing software pipelines and large data sets involving time series analysis and computer vision, in addition to interpersonal skills from a range of hospitality roles.

#### EMPLOYMENT

#### 2022 - Now

Innovative Technologies – Manchester

Position

Machine Learning Engineer

STACK

Python, Pytorch, Keras, Tensorflow, Numpy, Pandas, Sklearn, Git, Bash

DUTIES

- ICU performs accurate age verification to automate associated policy and allow access to age restricted purchases and premises, through an ensemble of various ML algorithms.
- Implemented bespoke methods from cutting edge research in SVM's, CNN's, and Bayesian Linear Regression which allow for statistically robust age verification.
- Designed a system by which spoof detection was achievable through the use of belief propagation and anomaly detection.
- Deployed trained models in resource-constrained environments.
- Worked remotely in an agile, communicative, and self-directed manner as part of a collaborative, interdisciplinary, diverse, and geographically-dispersed team.

2019 - 2020

Facebook (Meta) – London - Remote

Position

Data Scientist, Analytics Intern

Stack

Tableau, SQL, Python

Duties

- Performed large-scale data analysis to extract useful business insights.
- Identified the ones which were actionable, suggesting recommendations, and influenced the direction of the business by communicating the results to cross-functional groups.
- Classified leads so that the team could work on the most valuable cases, and suggested improvements in the tools and techniques to help scale the team.
- Created dashboards with Tableau on data obtained via SQL queries.

#### EDUCATION

2021 - 2022

Data Science, University of Bath

MSc Distinction, Master of Computer Science

Stack Python, SQL, Pytorch, Keras, Tensorflow, Sklearn, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn

Modules

Statistics for Data Science - Probability and statistics, with a focus on translating real-world problems into a mathematical framework in data science contexts.

**Machine Learning** - Covered both supervised and unsupervised machine learning algorithms from Bishop, including how to develop, evaluate and deploy trained models. The second semester involved advanced techniques focused on neural networks with both regression and classification.

Reinforcement Learning - Implemented various agents to solve environments from Sutton & Barto, including Dynamic Programming and Temporal Difference methods.

Bayesian Machine Learning - Implementing approaches such as inference and monte carlo.

2020 - 2021

Astronomy and Astrophysics, University of Manchester

MSc Distinction, Master of Physics

 ${\rm Research}$ 

Published a program to facilitate the data acquisition and analysis pipeline for TESS automatically, dubbed firefly (the best Sci-fi show!), which applies nested sampling (dynesty) to find best fit variables (TransitFit) between the host star and exoplanet.

2016 - 2020

Mathematics with Computer Science, University of Nottingham

MMATH Upper Second-Class Honours, Master of Mathematics

RESEARCH Dissertation involved working with python to numerically solve spherical cavitation bubble collapse.

2014 - 2016

Space Engineering, Loughborough College

A-Levels

Mathematics  $A^* \cdot Further Mathematics A \cdot Physics A \cdot Engineering A$ 

A specialised course focused on Engineering with guest lectures at the Space Centre in Leicester.

2009 - 2014

Secondary School, Loughborough College

GCSE's

Mathematics  $A^*$  · Further Mathematics A · Physics A · Biology B · Chemistry B · English A · English Literature A · Astronomy A

## GENERAL TECH STACK

## AWARDS AND QUALIFICATIONS

Language	Python, C++, LATEX, SQL	$\boldsymbol{2022}$	
PACKAGES	Numpy, Pandas, SciPy, AstroPy	$\boldsymbol{2021}$	Kaggle Competitions
ML PACKAGES	Sklearn, Tensorflow, PyTorch	2020	Tableau Desktop Specialist
$\mathbf{W}_{\mathbf{EB}}$	HTML, Markdown, CSS	2016	Full UK Driving Licence
SCIENTIFIC	Matlab, R, Fortran, Mathematica	2015	Grade 8 Violin
SOFTWARE	Microsoft Office, Tableau, Blender		

## **PUBLICATIONS**

AUTHOR -

CO-AUTHOR Hayes, J J C, E Kerins, J S Morgan et al. (2021) "TransitFit: an exoplanet transit fitting package for multi-telescope datasets and its application to WASP-127 b, WASP-91 b, and WASP-126

b", 1–14.

## ACADEMIC WORK EXPERIENCE

AUTUMN 2018	Scholarship, National University of Singapore
COHOL A DOLLID	Obtained a scholarchin to study a grash course in Karean language for 5 weeks and to learn abo

the culture and history of the changing landscapes of Singapore. Upon completion, applied to spend

the Autumn semester here successfully.

2017 - 2019 Physics Outreach, The University of Nottingham

Outreach I began, on a voluntary basis, promoting physics via social media which eventually evolved into a

paid role in which I mediated with events staff in the department to ensure successful participation.

Part of the role was ensuring inclusivity, and how best to target minority groups.

Summer 2018 Magical Maths – St Mary's Catholic Primary School, Nottingham

Role Organisation of weekly sessions to promote mathematics to primary school children, in line with

the national curriculum.

SUMMER 2014 Research Intern, Space Research Centre, The University of Leicester

INTERN During my first college year I gained work experience at the University of Leicester Space Research

Centre, assisting in the development of an astrobiology rock-sampling tool called SPLIT for use on

Mars

## Voluntary Positions and Responsibilities

	SPEAR, University of Manchester Actively contributing to exoplanet detection in the spearnet collaboration.	2021 - Now Researcher	ART-AI, University of Bath Collaborating with a large research group with an aim to educate interdisciplinary professional experts to make the best,
INTERESTS			and safest, use of artificial intelligence.
Рнотодкарну	Avid adventurer and keen	MUSIC	Self taught Guitar, Piano, Violin.

boundaries of my interest in both.

Escher, Bridget Riley etc.

Exploring the peaks, lakes and LITERATURE Love the classics, Jules Verne, H.P.

anywhere with hills. Love to spend

Lovecraft, H.G. Wells etc.

weeks away camping. General Into Sci fi and anything spacey!

REFERENCES

HIKING

NAME Dr. Eamonn Kerins Prof. Chris Harris Dr. John Holt

TITLE Senior Lecturer Research Professor Research Engineer

EMAIL eamonn.kerins@manchester.ac.uk University of Manchester University of Southampton University of Leicester

Department of Physics Fellow Department of Physics